tatateleservices.com 2003-06-21

# Privacy Policy for Tata Teleservices Limited’s website features

**The Privacy Policy for TATA Teleservices Limited’s website features.**

TATA Teleservices Limited’s own policies and procedures designed to ensure that the personal information provided by the customer visiting TATA Teleservices Limited’s website; www.TATATeleservices.com. is protected. 

Our privacy policy contains the following important information regarding your use of TATATeleservices.com: 

Collection of your personal information.  
How we use your personal information.  
Disclosure of your information.   
Security of your information that you may send to or receive from using TATATeleservices.com.   
How to access, correct or update your information.  
Children's privacy.  
What else you should know about privacy.  
How to contact us.

If you visit TATATeleservices.com, you are encouraged to read the information provided on the TATA Teleservices Limited site you are using. Information provided may be subject to change from time to time so we encourage you to check our online policies regularly. If you have any concerns or questions, please Contact Us. 

**Collection of your personal information**  
The types of personal information that we collect from you will depend on how you use TATATeleservices.com applying for TATATeleservices.com membership we will collect details such as your name, date of birth, education, email address, age, gender and some details of your personal interests. Some of this information is essential for us to be able to accurately identify who is using the service and as such is mandatory. Other types of information are collected to help us profile who is using the services and what their interests are. Information of this type is often optional – you need only fill it in if you wish to do so. For example you will have the option to provide the name of your Internet Service provider, your Internet usage, etc. TATA Teleservices Limited will endeavour to inform you what the information will be used for. 

We value your trust in TATATeleservices.com. In all cases, your information will be held in strictest confidence. 

TATATeleservices.com records other information as well. Whenever a page is requested from our web server, we record the time, date and URL of the request, along with information on the browser software that is being used. This information is used to improve the structure and performance of TATATeleservices.com, and is not used in any way to uniquely identify a user. 

TATATeleservices.com also uses cookies. Cookies are pieces of information that a website can transfer to an individual's computer hard drive for record keeping. Cookies can make using TATATeleservices.com easier by storing information about your preferences on a particular website. This will enable you to take full advantage of the services that TATATeleservices.com offers. The use of cookies is an industry standard and you'll find most major websites use them. Most Internet browsers are pre-set to accept cookies. If you prefer not to receive cookies, you can adjust your Internet browser to refuse cookies or to warn you when cookies are being used. 

**How we use your personal information**  
The personal information that you provide to us during registration is used for identification purposes and will assist you to subscribe to TATATeleservices.com services at any point of time in the future. 

The information we gather from your use of TATATeleservices.com enables us to provide better services that are tailored to your needs. Recording usage patterns helps us to identify the areas of our site that are popular and those that are not. By using cookies, users can specify their unique preferences. 

The data that is gathered when you use TATATeleservices.com is aggregated for analysis by TATA Teleservices Limited. 

Identifiable characteristics are removed and the user remains anonymous. Additional data provided to us is used to examine Internet trends and demographics to help TATA Teleservices Limited offer you improved online products and services. 

**Disclosure of your information**  
The information we collect from you will be kept strictly confidential. TATA Teleservices Limited will not reveal, disclose, sell, distribute, rent, licence, share or pass on to any third parties, other than those who are contracted to TATA Teleservices Limited, any personal information that you may have provided to us unless we have your express consent to do so. 

The following shall not constitute confidential Information: 

a) Information disclosed by a third party with out any obligation not to disclose the same. 

b) Information that is in the public domain through no act or default of either party hereto. 

c) Information developed independently by TATA Teleservices Limited without reliance on any confidential information received by you.

d) Information is already known to TATA Teleservices Limited without any obligation of confidentiality from a source other than you. 

Exceptions to disclosure of confidential information: 

\- where there are reasonable grounds to believe that disclosure is necessary to prevent a threat to life or health; and; 

\- where TATA Teleservices Limited is required to provide information in response to Subpoenas or Warrants or other legal processes and following statutory and legal requirements. 

Security of your information that you may send to or receive from using TATATeleservices.com  
Transmissions sent to or from TATATeleservices.com are routinely monitored for quality control and systems administration. 

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. While we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. These activities are conducted at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security. 

**How to access, correct or update your information**  
The information you provide to us is kept in a secure environment accessed only by authorised persons. You will always have access to the information and content that you provide to us. You can easily edit or delete your personal information, except for the mandatory items required for your membership application. You may access your information via the login screen. You will need your username and password to access and modify your registration information. 

**Children's privacy**  
The safety of children is very important to us.   
We ask that children under the age of 18 have a parent or guardian verify their membership application with TATATeleservices.com. Whilst TATATeleservices.com will make every reasonable effort to ensure that children's privacy and other rights are not compromised, it is ultimately the responsibility of parents to monitor their children's Internet usage. 

Children should always ask a parent before sending any transmission over the Internet. 

**What else you should know about privacy**  
Remember to close your browser when you have finished your user session. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. You as an individual are responsible for the security of and access to your own computer. 

Please be aware that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information over the Internet (for example: in discussion forums, via email, or in chat sites) that this information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information in publicly accessible online forums, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. 

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your username and passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you are using the Internet and TATATeleservices.com. 

**How to contact us**  
If you have any concerns or questions, please contact TATA Teleservices Limited by calling on the numbers mentioned at respective cities or use the Contact Us link to send your questions and comments via email.
